[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
Okay, so we've talked about how to represent documents and
好了 我们已讨论了如何表示文档
we've also talked about how to measure similarity between documents.
也讨论了如何衡量文档间的相似度
So now let's turn to the actual task of interest which is retrieving a document.
现在开始我们真正关心的任务 检索文档
So someone is reading an article, we're assuming they like that article and
某人正在阅读一篇文章 我们假设他很喜欢这篇文章
we'd like to present them with another article to read.
我们想给他推荐阅读其他文章
So in particular one of the most popular ways of doing this something called
对此 特别地 最热门的一种方法叫做
nearest neighbor search, where we have our query article.
最近邻域搜索 我们有查询文档
That's the article that were reading.
也就是正在读的这篇文章
And then there's the corpus.
以及语料库
That's all of the documents out there that we want to search over to
也就是我们搜索其中来推荐新文章的
recommend some new article.
所有文章的总和
And so what we need to do for
为了实现最近邻域搜索
our nearest neighbor search is we need to specify a distance metric.
我们需要定义一个距离
So this is gonna be our measure of similarity that we talked
此量用来衡量我们之前提过的
about earlier and
相似度
then what this algorithm is gonna output is a collection of related articles.
这个算法的输出是一个相关文章的集合
So one example of nearest neighbor search is something called one nearest neighbor,
最近邻域搜索的一个特例叫做最近邻搜索
where you have your query article and what you're gonna return is just simply
当搜索查询文档时 返回的
the most related article, out of all those articles out there, to the query article.
仅是搜索库中与查询文档最相关的一篇文章
And the algorithm is very straightforward.
这个算法很简单直接
We're just gonna search over every article in our corpus,
我们只需搜索语料库中的每篇文档
these are all these little green articles, and we're gonna compute the similarity
就是显示成绿色的这些 然后使用
using the methods that we described earlier between the query article and
之前提到的方法计算查询文档与语料库中的
this article we're examining in the corpus.
文档间的相似度
And then,
然后呢
if that similarity is better than the best similarity that we've found so far,
如果当前文档的相似度高于目前为止得到的所有相似度
then we're gonna keep this article as our best article that we've found so far.
我们将保留当前文档作为目前最优结果
And then at the end after we've iterated through every article in our corpus
在遍历过语料库中所有文档后
we're gonna look at what was the best article that we found.
我们则会将保留下来的最优选择
And we're gonna recommend this to the reader.
推荐给读者
A very straightforward variant of this is something called k- nearest neighbor
这种算法的一个简单变体叫做k-近邻搜索
search, where instead of just outputting the most relevant article that we've
与其输出查找到的最相关的一篇文章
found, we're gonna present the reader with a collection of k different articles
这个算法将返回最相关的k个不同的
that are the top k most relevant articles.
文章的集合给读者
And the way that we do this,
实现此目的的算法
the algorithm is newly identical except in instead of keeping just the most related
基本与前面相同 除了我们不仅要保留当前最相关的文章
article, we're gonna keep a priority queue of the top k articles found so far.
还需建立一优先队列来存放目前找到的k个最相关的文档 翻译: Emilily |审阅: Coursera Global Translator Community